



Sudharsan T S sudharsan.t.s@gmail.com DOB: 24-May-1988 Mobile No: 9886065140

Summary of Experience

Certified in Java (Oracle Certified Java Professional), Oracle (Oracle Certified Professional) and .Net (Microsoft Certified Professional). Very Good Experience in designing and building applications using Core Java, Servlet, JSP, Struts2, GWT using Weblogic and Websphere Application Server, Apache Tomcat. Energetic self-starter with excellent analytical and organizational skills. Achieves goals, objectives and milestones in timely and consistent manner.

Professional Experience

Company : Mavenir Systems (March 2012 – till date)

Work Experience : 11 months

Company : Tata Consultancy Services (January 2010 – March 2012)

Work Experience : 2 years 2 months

Technical Proficiency

Language Used : Core Java, Servlet, JSP, Struts2, GWT, Jasper Reports.

Database : Oracle 10g, MySQL

OS : Windows, UNIX.

Tools : BEA Weblogic Server, Websphere Server, Fortify

Scanner, Rational Clear case, Oracle SQL developer, Apache

CAS (Central Authentication Services), Open LDAP.

Others : Excellent problem-solving, organization and leadership Skills.

Skill Set

- Expertise in Core Java programming, JSP, Servlets, XML.
- Experience in Weblogic console, web applications.
- Good Understanding in using Tools like BEA Weblogic, Apache Tomcat, Fortify
 `Scanner (Security vulnerability assessment software), Eclipse, Edit Plus, SQL Plus,
 PL/SQL Developer, SONAR.
- Developed applications in GWT (Google Web Toolkit) which will make applications more powerful by implicitly integrating AJAX and the GUI appearance will look great and GWT technology is considered as a good replacement for Adobe Flex.

Achievements

- Completed Oracle Certified Java Developer (OCJP) in Java 6.
- Completed Oracle Certified Professional (OCP) in database developer side.
- Completed MCAD (Microsoft Certified Application Developer) in VB.Net. Microsoft Certification ID is 5962951.
- Elected as **LE** (Learning Enabler) in TCS which is given only for toppers in TCS training.
- Awarded with Certificate for Excellence for my work and innovative thoughts from client **TDA** (TD Ameritrade).

Project Details

1. Project Name: EIR (Equipment Identity Register)

Project Description	AirGuard EIR (Telecom product) is the equipment identity register, which helps
	network operators control illegal use of mobile equipment on their network. It
	includes Equipment checking which will return the status of the mobile(white,
	black, grey), Mobile Station List which will lock some handsets to specific
	subscribers, Cloned Handset list which will allow the same handset IMEI no's
	to be used by several subscribers.
Company	Mavenir Systems (Telecom procuct based company).
Working Period	March 2012 – till date.

Role	 I was responsible for analyzing the requirements and identifying the best open source software's available for implementing it. I was also responsible for implementing the Single Sign-On solution to the existing product using Apache CAS (Central Authentication Services) and Open LDAP (SYMAS distribution). I and My team were responsible for migrating the existing product to a new version to which the product will have all the latest technologies and security feature.
Environment	Java/J2EE, Open LDAP, CAS (Central Authentication Services), Apache Tomcat.
Team Size	15

2. Project Name: eFiling

Project Description	The eFiling application is an electronic records management system being used by Swiss Re offices across locations. Its services include inducting, indexing, sharing and searching of documents between business functions.
Client	Swiss Re.
Working Period	May 2011 – Mar 2012.
Role	 I was responsible for developing many business functionality required for eFiling application using Core Java. I was also responsible for developing GUI's using GWT (Google Web Toolkit) which is a booming technology and also a good replacement for Adobe Flex.
Environment	GWT (Google Web Toolkit), Documentum, Oracle 11g.
Team Size	8

3. Project Name: TCS BaNCS

Project Description	TCS BaNCS is a world renowned product for Financial Services oriented companies and it comprises of very huge modules. I was working for "SI Arch" module which has the functionality for DBA's to create the user and user group for the application using 4/6 eyes model, sending alert notification in the form of email and Fax, generating the reports using integrated Jasper software, security management.
Client	Deutsche Bank, Morgan Stanley, HSBC.

Worked Period	May 2010 – Apr 2011
Role	 I was developing new modules for the project according to the new requirements from various clients or customizing the requirement if it is already available. I was responsible for developing new pages using JSP and business logic for the "Arch" team of TCS BaNCS. I was responsible for fixing the code vulnerability using Fortify scanner to make the BaNCS product more secure to prevent threats from hacking from anonymous people. I had nearly fixed about more than 6000 issues which include Cross-Site scripting, SQL Injection and improved the performance of the software by following good coding principles for Java. I was also responsible for fixing the bugs reported from the clients. I was deploying the web applications after building from the maven script.
Environment	BEA Weblogic server, Core Java, JSP, Fortify Scanner.
Team Size	25

Educational Qualification

- Completed **B.E** in **Computer Science and Engineering** from **Anna University** with an aggregate of **86%**
- Completed XII standard from **Bharati Matriculation Higher Secondary School** with 92.91%

Personal Profile

Date of Birth : 24-May-1988

Marital Status : Single

Nationality : Indian